Every saga has a beginning.
Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace is a adventure, action,
science fiction film directed by George Lucas.
Anakin Skywalker, a young slave strong with the
Force, is discovered on Tatooine.
Meanwhile, the evil Sith have returned, enacting
their plot for revenge against the Jedi.
Qui-Gon Jinn, played by Liam Neeson.
Obi-Wan Kenobi, played by Ewan McGregor.
Padmé Amidala, played by Natalie Portman.
Anakin Skywalker, played by Jake Lloyd.
Senator Palpatine, played by Ian McDiarmid.
Shmi Skywalker, played by Pernilla August.
Star Wars Episode I: Racer is a 1999 racing video game
developed and published by LucasArts.
It is based on the podracing sequence in the film Star
Wars: Episode I – The Phantom Menace.
The game features all of the racers and race course
on Tatooine from The Phantom Menace.
It adds several new courses, on Tatooine and various planets.
The game has several single player modes, including a tournament mode.
The format of multiplayer mode varies by platform.
Jake Lloyd and Lewis MacLeod, who portrayed Anakin Skywalker and Sebulba in
The Phantom Menace, reprise their film roles in the game.
Episode I: Racer received generally positive reviews from critics.
Several major media outlets listed it as one of the top Star Wars video games.
As of 2011, the game holds the Guinness record as the best-selling sci-fi racing game, with
worldwide sales of 3.12 million units, followed by series like Wipeout and F-Zero.
Two podracing games were released later.
Star Wars: Racer Arcade, an arcade game featuring many similar
tracks and characters, was released in 2000.
A sequel, Star Wars Racer Revenge was released in 2002 for the PlayStation 2.
Twenty years after the release of the game, it received an HD
re-release for Nintendo Switch and PlayStation 4 in June 2020.
It was later released on Xbox One in October 2020.
The film explores themes of galaxy, senate, taskmaster, prophecy, queen.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.